SAINT PAUL AREA YMCA (MINN.).:
Saint Paul Area YMCA records.
1856-1999.
Minnesota Historical Society
Saint Paul Area YMCA (Minn.).
Minutes, constitution and by-laws, annual meeting materials, financial and committee records, correspondence, transcripts of newspaper articles, subject files, branch files, camp files, photographs, and scrapbooks containing information on the St. Paul (Minn.) area YMCA's many programs and activities for youths and adults.
31 cubic feet (30 boxes).
SCOPE AND CONTENTS
The collection includes a fairly complete set of minutes of the board of directors and executive committee, the metropolitan business and finance committee, and the nominating committee. There are also minutes for the physical department committee, and the "Y's Menette's Club," a women's organization. Other corporate records include annual meeting programs and minutes, board of directors rosters, and audits. Subject files relate program development, construction programs, and planning.
Extensive publicity scrapbooks, and several scrapbooks kept by various units within the organization, consist largely of newspaper clippings.
A substantial collection of photographs document the many activities and programs of the YMCA. Included are depictions of youth and adult groups covering all aspects of the program, including sports, dancing, meetings, conferences, and music and theatrical groups. They include many photographs of the various branches throughout St. Paul, particularly in relation to building construction, and a set of identified portraits.
CATALOG HEADINGS
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the catalog of the Minnesota Historical Society. Researchers desiring materials about related topics should search the catalog using these headings.
Topics:
Amateur theater -- Minnesota -- Saint Paul.; Athletics -- Minnesota -- Saint Paul.; Boys -- Minnesota -- Saint Paul -- Societies and clubs.; Girls -- Minnesota -- Saint Paul -- Societies and clubs.; Men -- Minnesota -- Saint Paul -- Societies and clubs.; Pageants -- Minnesota -- Saint Paul.; Young adults -- Minnesota -- Saint Paul.; Young Men's Christian associations -- Minnesota -- Saint Paul -- Administration.; Youth -- Minnesota -- Saint Paul -- Societies and clubs.
Persons:
Driscoll, Arthur Brown, 1862-1938.; Funk, John Philip.; Ingersoll, Daniel Wesley, 1812-1894.; Nye, Herbert.; Stassen, Harold Edward, 1907-2001.
Organizations:
Methodist Episcopal Church -- Minnesota -- Saint Paul.; Saint Paul Young Men's Christian Association -- Buildings.; Saint Paul Young Men's Christian Association -- Libraries.; Saint Paul Young Men's Christian Association.; St. Paul YMCA Players (Minn.).; United Nations.; Young Men's Christian Association of St. Paul (Saint Paul, Minn.).
Places:
Saint Paul (Minn.)
Document Types:
Photographs.
ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION
Accession Information:
Accession numbers: 3481; 8118; 10,955; 11,340; 11,343; 11,551; 12,064; 12,128; 12,463; 13,246; 14,303; 16,131; 16,349
DETAILED DESCRIPTION
- Board and Administrative Files
  - Constitution and bylaws, 1887-1941. (7)
  - Constitutions, articles of incorporation, and bylaws (17)
  - 1940-1979., 12 folders.
  - Correspondence and miscellaneous papers, undated and 1848-1944.; 4 folders. (7)
    Includes undated histories.
  - Report of the General Secretary, 1914-1917.
  - Transcripts of newspaper articles about the St. Paul YMCA, 1856-1910.; 4 folders.
  - Minutes of Meetings of the Board of Directors:
    Arranged in chronological order.
    - Volume 1, September 8, 1856-November 1, 1858.
    - Volume 2, June 1, 1878-February 24, 1898.
    - Volume 3, February 24, 1898-April 6, 1909.
    - Volume 4. Minutes and Committee Reports, November 4, 1909-February 6, 1912. (9)
    - Volume 5, October 4, 1912-October 8, 1914. (7)
      In reverse chronological order.
    - January 13, 1913-October 23, 1929., 2 folders.
    - November 19, 1929-December 31, 1947., 8 folders. (8)
    - January 30, 1948-December 30, 1953., 7 folders. (9)
    - January 28, 1954-February 26, 1960., 6 folders.
  - Volume 6. Joint Committee, April 12, 1897-January 27, 1898. (7)
  - Volume 7. Minutes of Meetings, Student branch, January 14, 1896-March 7, 1912.
  - Historical information. (1)
  - Physical Department Committee minutes, 1914-1949.
  - Y’s Menette’s Club of St. Paul minutes, 1942-1961.; 6 folders.
  - Board of Directors and Executive Committee minutes:
    - March 1961-September 1970., 15 folders.
    - October 1970-May 24, 1978., 20 folders. (2)
    - May 25, 1978-December 1981., 9 folders. (3)
  - Annual meeting, 1929-1989.; 6 folders.
    Includes annual reports and programs. Files from 1960-1981 include minutes. There are no meeting records for the year 1945.
  - Roster: Board of Directors, Boards of Management, and committee organization, 1976-1981.
  - Board of Directors resource packet, 1980.
  - A.B. Driscoll papers, 1907-1967.; 3 folders.
  - Correspondence from civic leaders following 1928 retirement (1929) and miscellaneous materials.
  - Business and Finance Committee minutes:
    - 1967-1972., 6 folders.
    - 1974-1976., 3 folders. (4)
  - Annual audits, 1965-1979.
    Incomplete.
  - Nominating Committee records, 1972-1974.; 2 folders.
  - Program plans, 1949/50, 1965/66, 1971 and 1972.
  - Development and building, 1977 and 1981.
  - Corporate planning process report, 1980.
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1918-1978.
    [.5 cubic feet empty]
- Subject files
  - American Indian Center Project, 1968-1970.; 2 folders. (17)
  - Amortization Projects: Purchase of Properties, 1965-1967.
  - Annual meetings, programs and minutes, 1950-1990.
  - Anniversaries (75th), 1931.
  - Anniversaries (100th), 1956.
  - Board of Directors:
    - How We Work Together, 1976.
    - Minutes, 1977-1978, 1981.
    - Resolution on check signing, 1970-1978.
  - Brochures, undated.
  - Camping Task Force, 1976.
  - Capital Campaign, 1985.; 2 folders.
  - Catholic Church and the YMCA:
    - St. Paul and Minneapolis Archdiocese, 1956-1968.; 5 folders.
    - National Council for Ecumenical Consultation, 1966.
  - Corporate goals and objectives, 1973 and beyond, circa 1973.
  - Deficit: financial alternatives, 1972-1973.
  - Deficit reduction, 1972-1973.
  - Distinguished leader award, 1973-1989.
  - Euclid Hotel, 1967-1972. (18)
  - History of the St. Paul YMCA:
    - General information files, 1909-1986.; 3 folders.
    - Minnesota Historical Society, 1925-1999., 2 folders.
    - Writing of the history, 1955-1957.
    - Philosophy of the St. Paul YMCA, undated.
    - One Hundred Years of Fellowship and Service 1856-1956: The Story of the St. Paul Young Men's Christian Association., Bill, Alfred Hoyt.
  - Minnesota State-Trust supervision, 1975.
  - National YMCA: Purpose and Paris Basis Study, 1968-1972.
  - National Council: International Division Program Center, 1978-1979.
  - National Council Reports, 1975-1979.
  - National Youth Project Using Mini-Bikes, 1976.
  - Program plans and policies, 1960/1961-1972.; 7 folders.
  - Racism, 1972.
  - Recognition events:
    - Tony Bechik, July 19, 1978.
    - Paul Bremicker, September 7, 1961.
    - Warren E. Burger, 1969-1972.
    - Ernie Collingham, September 20, 1972.
    - Clifford E. Comfort, April 16, 1963.
    - Ted Gray, September 12, 1974.
    - Phil R. Hall, June 26, 1979.; 3 folders.
    - John R. Mott, 1955.
    - Roger B. Shepard, Jr., August 20, 1969.
    - Henry Setzer, September 25, 1978.
    - Robert Tucker, October 7, 1974.
  - Service Honor Roll: YMCA Building Fund Campaign, 1947.
  - Stationary samples, circa 1913.
  - Social Security, 1950-1976.
  - St. Paul YMCA tax ruling, 1981.
  - Student branch, 1948-1969.
  - YMCA Players: Liberty Ho! program and score, 1938.; 2 folders.
  - YMCA Players theatrical productions, programs and news clippings, 1935-1943.
- Branch Files
  - Downtown St. Paul YMCA: (19)
    - Program plans, 1945-1947; 1950-1952.; 2 folders.
    - Building renovation, 1958.
    - City office remodeling, 1962.
    - General files, 1972-1984.; 22 folders.
    - Skyway-East branch general files, 1985-1998.; 15 folders.
  - East Branch:
    - Program plans and policies, 1965-1966.
    - Land purchase, 1960-1967.; 2 folders.
    - General files, 1971-1988.; 25 folders.
  - Midway Branch:
    - Bylaws, 1951-1955.
    - Committee of Management, 1964-1969.
    - Leonard, Jody: Lawsuit (Midway pool collapse), 1973-1974.
    - Midway pool ceiling collapse, 1968-1973.
    - Midway pool ceiling replacement, 1972.
    - General files, 1953, 1972-1998.; 32 folders. (20)
  - Northeast Branch:
    - General files, 1967-1998.; 38 folders.
  - Northwest Suburban Branch:
    - Five year plan, 1974.
    - Committee of Management, 1965-1967.
    - Minutes, 1968-1969.
    - Background paper, 1966.
    - General files, 1964-1998.; 33 folders. (21)
  - South Branch:
    - Riverview branch, 1950.
      Called Tri-Town in 1954 and South District in 1958.
    - South district builiding committee, 1963-1964.
    - Tri-town building site, 1958.
    - South Branch property purchase, 1963.
    - Committee of Management, 1963-1969.
    - General files, 34 folders.
  - Southeast Branch:
    - General files, 1990-1998.; 10 folders.
  - Southwest Branch: (22)
    - General files, 1990-1998.; 9 folders.
  - St. Croix Valley Branch:
    - General files, 1992-1998.; 8 folders.
- Camp Files
  - Camp Du Nord: (22)
    - Annual reports, 1984-1986, 1988.
    - Bylaws, 1964-1965.
    - Finance committee, 1960-1963.
    - General files, 1973-1997.; 30 folders.
  - Camp Northland:
    - General files, 1983-1989.; 8 folders.
  - Camp St. Croix: (23)
    - Annual reports, 1980-1981, 1984-1987.; 3 folders.
    - Master plan report, 1966.
    - Five year plan, May 1985.
    - Voices of St. Croix: The First 90 Years, 1999.
    - Annual reports, 1967-1971.
    - St. Croix land survey, 1964-1966.
    - Headquarters: fire loss and replacement, 1968.
    - Railroad right of way purchase, 1966.
    - Real estate taxes, 1965-1973.
    - Cabin project, 1959-1960.
    - Dining Hall-Conference Center, 1973-1976.
    - Map of camp, undated.
    - Planning for the future, 1973.
    - Troy Township zoning ordinance, 1964.
    - Wisconsin state taxes, 1969.
    - Northern States Power Company property acquisition, 1967-1968.
    - General files, 1965-1992.; 39 folders.
    - General files, 1994-1999.; 8 folders. (24)
  - Camp Widjiwagan:
    - Pictures, maps, brochures, 1938-1960.
    - Newspaper clippings, 1962.
    - Brauer campsite study, 1967.
    - Thor's Lodge dining hall, 1998.
    - Summer schedule brochure, 1999.
    - General files, 1971-1991.; 29 folders.
    - General files, 1992-1998.; 7 folders. (25)
- Photograph materials
  - Philip C. Dittes negatives, 1948-1965.; 4" x 5" and smaller. (25)
    Prints of the negatives appear scattered throughout the photographic files.
  - Annual meetings, 1936-1974.; 17 folders.
  - Barn Dance, 1941.
  - Basketball.
  - Beckman-Kirby Page dinner, 1939.
  - Boxing.
  - Boys Department reunion, 1941.
  - Boys Department, 1943.
  - Boys Division, 1925-1960.; 17 folders.
  - Boys division canoe trip, 1937.
  - Boys Division tumbling team, 1944-1945.; 2 folders.
  - Building, Central YMCA.
  - Building campaign, 1947.
  - Building completion campaign, 1952.
  - Business Men's Club, 1938.
  - Business Men's Club Christmas dinner.
  - Business Men's Folder, 1950.
  - Business Men's Professional Club.
  - Cafeteria.
  - Camera Club.
  - Capital funds program.
  - Centennial, 1951.
  - Centennial dinner, 1944.
  - Centennial meeting, 1956.
  - Central Branch, 1942, 1946-1947.; 3 folders.
  - Church Athletic Association, 1946-1953.; 4 folders.
  - Co-ed program, 1946-1947, 1951.; 3 folders.
  - CPR.
  - Delta Club. (26)
  - Dormitory Council, 1945.
  - Downtown Branch, 1956, 1961.
  - Downtown Committee, 1952.
  - Downtown remodeling, 1947.
  - Dry night club.
  - DuNord.
  - East Branch/East District, undated and 1937-1963.; 11 folders.
  - East Side building.
  - Empo Club.
  - Fall planning conference, 1927, 1931-1946.; 6 folders.
  - Fall Prom, 1941.
  - Family swim, 1937, 1946.; 2 folders.
  - Father and Son Stag, 1937-1942.; 3 folders.
  - Fire.
  - Fisherman's luncheon, 1939.
  - Folk dancing.
  - Foreign work, 1937.
  - Founder's Day/Week, 1935-1941.; 6 folders.
  - Friday Nighters.
  - Future Champions of America.
  - Golden Ball basketball game, 1941.
  - Grade: Y.
  - Gymnastic squad.
    Includes tickets to First Annual Indoor Athletic Meet, 1908.
  - Handball, 1938-1947.; 4 folders.
  - Health Service.
  - Health Week, 1938-1939.; 3 folders.
  - Hi-Hop, 1944-1947.; 5 folders.
  - High School activities, 1945-1965.
  - High School dancing class, 1947.
  - High School groups, 1946.
  - High School gym meet, 1938.
  - High School Swimming Association, 1937, 1939.; 2 folders.
  - High School YMCA Forum, 1945-1947.; 3 folders.
  - History, writing of, 1955.
  - Hi-Y, 1946-1962.; 5 folders.
  - Hi-Y Officers Training Conference, 1945.
  - Hi-Y Youth and Government Program, 1946.
  - Hobby Club.
    Includes wood shop.
  - Hyperion Club, 1935-1937.; 2 folders.
  - I.C.E.P., 1965.
  - Indian Guide Club.
  - Indian guides, undated and 1941-1969.; 3 folders.
  - Lake Placid Party, 1937-1938.
  - Levee Center, undated and 1930s.
  - Liberty Ho!
  - Life members, 1954-1968.; 8 folders.
  - Lounge, 1948.
  - Membership campaign, 1925-1961.; 27 folders.
  - Membership round-up, 1962, 1964-1966.; 4 folders.
  - Membership enrollment, 1968.
  - Men's Division golf tournament, 1938.
  - Men's Division picnic, 1937-1938.; 2 folders.
  - Men's Club, 1937, 1940.; 2 folders.
  - Midway YMCA, 1939-1953, 1958, 1995.; 5 folders.
    Includes brochures.
  - Modernization folder, 1936.
  - Monroe Hi-Y Club.
  - National Volleyball Tournament, 1942.
  - New building.
  - New Years.
  - New Year's dance, 1940-1942.; 2 folders.
  - Noon workout Christmas party, 1941.
  - Noon gym class, 1941, 1946.; 2 folders.
  - North Central Area Conference, 1937-1938.; 3 folders.
  - Northeast Branch, 1967, 1970-1971.; 3 folders.
  - Northwest Airlines.
  - Northwest Branch, 1960-1971.; 2 folders.
  - Old building. (27)
  - One hundred first anniversary.
  - One hundred second anniversary.
  - Operation Big Wheel.
  - Palavan Club, 1937-1946.; 2 folders.
  - Personality Growth Institute, 1938-1940.; 5 folders.
  - Phalanx fraternity, 1938-1940.; 2 folders.
  - Physical Department, 1901-1957.; 8 folders.
  - P.Q. Luncheon, 1942.
  - Program Committee, 1946.; 2 folders.
  - Red Triangle Club, 1946.
  - Retired Men's Club, 1956.
  - Riverboat program.
  - Safety Quiz contest.
  - Sea Horse Club.
  - S.E.R.A. classes, 1935.
  - Semper Fidelis Glee Club, undated.
  - Service men, 1945-1946.; 3 folders.
  - Shingle Creek Village.
  - South Youth Choir.
  - South District Branch, 1958-1975.; 2 folders.
  - South Family Branch dedication, 1970.; 2 folders.
  - Spotlight, 1945.
  - Spring Frolic, May 24, 1941.
  - Square Dance Group, 1946-1947, 1949.; 2 folders.
  - Staff, 1946-1947, 1973.; 4 folders.
  - Staff and laymen retreat, Camp St. Croix, 1973.
  - Student Branch, 1947.
  - Summer Fun Club, 1945-1963.; 8 folders.
  - Swimming, 1931-1959.; 13 folders.
    Includes Learn-to-Swim program.
  - Swimming beach party, 1941.
  - Swing shift party, 1943.
  - Taffy sale.
  - Teen canteen, 1947.
  - Tuberculosis clinics, undated.
  - Triad Club, 2 folders.
  - University of Life.
  - Vavoulis (George) trip.
  - Vikings training camp visit, 1965.
  - Volleyball.
  - Volleyball Dutch Lunch, 1939.
  - Volleyball get together, 1935.
  - Weight lifting, 1945.; 2 folders.
  - West Publishing, 1946.; 2 folders.
  - Winter Carnival, 1937.
  - Wood shop.
  - World Service, 1947, 1966.; 3 folders.
  - Wrestlers, boxers, karate, undated and 1938-1940.
  - Y Camera Club.
  - Y.M.D.
  - Y.M.D. dances.
  - Y.M.D. golf tournament, 1937, 1941.; 2 folders.
  - YMCA building, downtown, undated and 1910, 1936-1958.
  - YMCA Church League, 1950.
  - YMCA historical.
  - YMCA pageant.
  - YMCA players:
    - Miscellaneous.
    - The great adventure, 1935.
    - Double door, 1936.
    - Barchester towers, 1937.
    - First lady, 1937.
    - Death takes a holiday, 1938.
    - Cinderella house, 1938.
    - Journey's end, 1938.
    - Down to victory, 1939.
    - Poor dear Edgar, 1939.
    - Laburnum Grove, 1940.
    - Passing third floor back, 1940.
    - Her husband's wife, 1940.
    - As the clock strikes, 1941.
    - Fresh fields, 1941.
    - Rain on the roof, 1941.
    - Productions, 1935-1947.; 3 folders.
    - General, 1942-1947.; 4 folders.
  - Y's Menettes, 1939.
  - Y-Gang League, miscellaneous, 1936-1937, 1939.; 3 folders.
  - Y Men's Club, 1928-1940.; 28 folders. (28)
  - Young Men's Division, 1926-1941.
  - Youth in Government Program, 1946.
  - Youthmobile, undated and 1971.; 2 folders.
  - Portraits:
    - Anderson, Charles, 1963.
    - Anderson, John Tracy, 1962.
    - Ball, Armand, 1962, 1967.
    - Bechik, Anthony, undated and 1952, 1969.
    - Beckman, Fredrick W., undated and 1932, 1939.
    - Behrends, William S., undated.
    - Bertelsen, Sig A., undated and 1947.
    - Bevenius, Ingvar, 1963.
    - Bigelow, Charles H. Jr., circa 1944-1949.
    - Bigelow, Frederic R., undated.
    - Bjorklund, Frederick, undated.
    - Board of Directors, 1937, 1958, 1969.
    - Bremicker, Paul B., circa 1944-1961.
    - Brownlow, Kent S., 1963.
    - Caldwell, G. James, 1949-1955.
    - Carlson, Richard L, Jr., 1959.
    - Collingham, Ernest Jr., 1946, 1948, circa 1969-1972.
    - Comfort, Clifford E., 1952, circa 1958-1963.
    - Dane, Royden S., circa 1939.
    - Dean, William J., circa 1912-1923.
    - Dickey, Eugene, undated.
    - Dickson, Dr. T. H., circa 1934-1944.
    - Dietrich, Richard, 1965.
    - Dietz, Charlton, 1977.
    - Eyinck, Henning G., circa 1956.
    - Ferrari, Helen, 1942.
    - Gamble, Sidney D., 1970.
    - Gardner, Truman, undated.
    - Godfrey, Otis, 1974.
    - Grace, Edward, circa 1898-1912.
    - Gray, Ted, undated.
    - Hanson, Jack, 1955.
    - Headley, Louis S., circa 1928-1932.
    - Hoffman, Richard, 1977.
    - Holmer, O. Geoffrey, 1932, 1936-1937, 1947.
    - Hunting, Earl B., 1933, 1938.
    - Jenckes, undated.
    - Jentinck, Norm, undated.
    - Johnson, Paul A., undated.
    - Johnson, Judy, undated.
    - Johnson, Stuart A., 1977.
    - Jordan, Parker, undated.
    - Kanne, Gerald M., 1976.
    - Kirk, Everett B., undated.
    - Kochendorfer, Robert L., undated.
    - LaJoie, Larry, 1962.
    - LeMaster, William L., 1943.
    - Lindeke, Al Jr., undated.
    - Lorentzen, Norman, 1980.
    - MacDonald, Wayne A., 1970.
    - Mayo, Gail, undated.
    - McCarthy, Eugene R., 1970.
    - Melander, Art, 1963.
    - Miller, Ralf, 1956.
    - Moren, John A., 1947.
    - Morgan, Samuel, undated.
    - Mundt, Logan, undated, 1938, 1946.
    - Murray, Eugene R., undated.
    - Nelson, Emil H., undated and 1939.
    - Nelson, Norman, undated and 1947, 1955.
    - Nye, Harry, undated.
    - Oehler, Cole, circa 1955-1958.
    - Paisley, Manley, undated.
    - Paulson, Leonard, circa 1927-1928.
    - Payne, Donald M., 1970.
    - Phillips, Guybert M., circa 1947.
    - Rock, Walter J., undated.
    - Scott, W. A., circa 1912-1914.
    - Shepard, Roger B. Jr., circa 1963-1969.
    - Sideen, Wesley, undated.
    - Skellet, Oliver T., circa 1947.
    - Stanelle, Robert, 1969.
    - Stanton, Richard, 1968.
    - Stewart, Jacob H., circa 1860s.
    - Stone, John, 1938, 1943.
    - Tani, Robert, 1963.
    - Thompson, J. R., circa 1914-1927, 1938.
    - Thorsell, John F., undated.
    - Traver, John L., 1967.
    - Tucker, Robert H., 1976.
    - Williams, George, undated.
  - 2006 History book.
  - Distinguished leaders awards ceremony, 1972-1977.
  - Miscellaneous, 8 folders.
  - Two oversize portraits, undated. (30)
  - Executive Committee and Chairmen of Six Committees of Management portrait, 1956.
- Scrapbooks
  - Volume 8. Student branch, undated. (9)
  - Volume 9. Printed materials, 1906-1910.
  - Volume 10. Publicity, 1908-191922.
  - Volume 11. Publicity, 1910-1912.
  - Volume 12. Publicity, 1910-1915. (10)
  - Volume 13. Publicity, 1922-1930.
  - Volume 14, Physical Department, 1929-[1930?].
  - Volume 15. Publicity, 1930-1932.
  - Volume 16. Publicity, 1932-1933. (11)
  - Volume 17. Publicity, 1933-1934.
  - Volume 18. Publicity, 1934-1935.
  - Volume 19. Publicity, 1935-1936.
  - Volume 20. Publicity, 1936.
  - Volume 21. Publicity, 1936-1937. (12)
  - Volume 22. Publicity, 1937-1938.
  - Volume 23. Publicity, 1938-1939.
  - Volume 24, Third Annual Hobby Show, 1939.
  - Volume 25. Publicity, 1939-1941.
  - Volume 26, Fourth Annual Hobby Show, 1940. (13)
  - Volume 27. Publicity, 1940-1942.
  - Volume 28, Physical Department, 1940-1942.
  - Volume 29, Fifth Annual Hobby Show, 1941.
  - Volume 30. Publicity, 1941-1942.
  - Volume 31. Publicity, 1942-1944.
  - Volume 32, Centennial membership campaign, 1944.
  - Volume 33. Publicity, 1944-1945.
  - Volume 34. Publicity, 1945-1946. (14)
  - Volume 35. Publicity, 1946-1947.
  - Volume 36, Building fund campaign, 1947.
  - Volume 37. Publicity, 1947-1948.
  - Volume 38. Publicity, 1949-1950.
  - Volume 39. Publicity, 1950-1951. (15)
  - Volume 40. Publicity, 1951-1953.
  - Volume 41. Publicity, 1953-1955.
  - Volume 42. Publicity, 1955-1957.
  - Volume 43. Publicity, 1957-1959.
  - Volume 44. Publicity, 1959-1960. (16)
  - Volume 45. Publicity, 1960-1962.
  - Volume 46. Publicity, 1962-1963.
  - Volume 47. Publicity, 1963-1964.
  - Volume 48. Publicity, 1964-1965.
  - Volume 49. Publicity, 1965-1966.
  - Publicity, April 1966-October 1971.; 6 volumes. (5)
  - Publicity, December 1973-December 1974.; 2 volumes. (6)
  - Central Hi-Y Club, 1921-1940.; 1 volume.
  - YMCA Co-ed Club, 1949. (29)
  - 1969- August 1972.
  - November 1971 - December 1972.
  - October 1977 - June 1979.
  - July 1979 - February 1982. (30)
  - November 1982-January 1989.
- Other Graphic materials
  - Architectural drawing, 1075 Arcade Street [East YMCA], undated. (30)
  - Proposed East Side YMCA, St. Paul, William M. Ingemann and Milton V. Bergstedt, architects, undated.